<?xml version="1.0"?>
<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20230417</CreaDate><CreaTime>09292300</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate>20241010</ModDate><ModTime>093412</ModTime><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange><ArcGISProfile>ItemDescription</ArcGISProfile></Esri><toolbox name="WildfireExposure" alias="toolbox"><arcToolboxHelpPath>c:\program files\arcgis\pro\Resources\Help\gp</arcToolboxHelpPath><toolsets/></toolbox><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>WildfireExposure</resTitle></idCitation><idPurp>This ArcGIS Python Toolbox, developed in collaboration with Dr. Jennifer Schmidt, Institute for Social and Economic Research (ISER) at the University of Alaska Anchorage, is designed to allow users to calculate wildfire hazard fuels and exposure values from gridded vegetation data, as described in:

Schmidt, J.I., Ziel, R.H., Calef, M.P. et al. Spatial distribution of wildfire threat in the far north: exposure assessment in boreal communities. Nat Hazards 120, 4901–4924 (2024). https://doi.org/10.1007/s11069-023-06365-4

The toolbox was designed for replicating the described exposure assessment, and expanding to additional areas, in a user-friedly and repeatable way. Processing methods include the calculation of hazard fuels layers at 100 and 500 meter distances, exposure layers at 100 and 500 meter distances, and a combined exposure layer that assigns the values from the 100 meter exposure within a 500m buffer distance of a buildings layer, and the 500 meter exposure values outside those areas. Intermediate products are also created and saved, and the tool can use previously generated intermediate products as inputs to limit processing time.</idPurp><idCredit>Geographic Information Network of Alaska (University of Alaska Fairbanks), Institute for Social and Economic Research (University of Alaska Anchorage)</idCredit><searchKeys><keyword>Wildfire</keyword><keyword>Hazard</keyword><keyword>Exposure</keyword></searchKeys></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName>ArcToolbox Toolbox</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20240918</mdDateSt></metadata>
